<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Total Loss &#8211; Normand</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.normandpllc.com/practice-area/total-loss/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.normandpllc.com</link>
	<description>We Are Results</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 18:15:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.normandpllc.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/cropped-Normand_Favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Total Loss &#8211; Normand</title>
	<link>https://www.normandpllc.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Volino v Progressive Casuality insurance</title>
		<link>https://www.normandpllc.com/case-studies/volinoprogressivecasualityinsurance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 20:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.normandpllc.com/?post_type=case-study&#038;p=933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT SOUTHERN DISTRICT OF NEW YORK CIVIL ACTION NO. 1:21-cv-6243-LGS In the case of Volino v. Progressive Casuality Insurance the Plaintiffs alleged in this Action that the total-loss software licensed by Defendants, Mitchell International, Inc.’s (“Mitchell”) WorkCenter Total Loss (“WCTL”), applies an improper adjustment called the projected sold adjustment (“PSA”) in settling... <a href="https://www.normandpllc.com/case-studies/volinoprogressivecasualityinsurance/" class="more-link"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 45.05 13.13"><polyline class="read-more-arrow" points="0.5 0 0.5 6.5 44 6.5"/><polyline class="read-more-arrow" points="38 0.45 44.34 6.79 38.35 12.78"/></svg>Read More</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-large-font-size">UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT SOUTHERN DISTRICT OF NEW YORK CIVIL ACTION NO. 1:21-cv-6243-LGS</p>



<p>In the case of Volino v. Progressive Casuality Insurance the Plaintiffs alleged in this Action that the total-loss software licensed by Defendants, Mitchell International, Inc.’s (“Mitchell”) WorkCenter Total Loss (“WCTL”), applies an improper adjustment called the projected sold adjustment (“PSA”) in settling total-loss claims, resulting in an underpayment of claims, breach of Defendants’ New York automobile insurance policies and violation of GBL section 349. Counsel for the Parties have engaged in arm’s-length negotiations on the terms of an Agreement. Class Counsel conducted investigation and completed discovery relating to the claims brought against Defendants, analyzed the legal issues in this case, and engaged in substantial motion practice and trial preparation over almost three years of litigation. The Defendants deny and continue to deny all material allegations in the Action<br>and maintain they complied with the automobile insurance policies and all applicable laws. Still, Normand PLLC was able to obtain a settlement agreement on July 1, 2024 for a sum of $48,000,000. Learn more about our <a href="https://www.normandpllc.com/practice-area/total-loss/" data-type="practice-area" data-id="11">total loss</a> practice area. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carrie Andrews v. State Auto Mutual Insurance Company</title>
		<link>https://www.normandpllc.com/case-studies/carrie-andrews-v-state-auto-mutual-insurance-company/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 02:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.normandpllc.com/?post_type=case-study&#038;p=770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT SOUTHERN DISTRICT OF OHIO EASTERN DIVISION CASE NO.: 2:21-CV-05867-ALM-CMV “On October 25, 2023, the Court in Andrews, et al. v. State Auto Mutual Insurance Company (S.D. Oh.) approved a class action settlement. The case revolved around allegations of breach of contract by the insurer, State Auto Mutual Insurance Company, for failing to... <a href="https://www.normandpllc.com/case-studies/carrie-andrews-v-state-auto-mutual-insurance-company/" class="more-link"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 45.05 13.13"><polyline class="read-more-arrow" points="0.5 0 0.5 6.5 44 6.5"/><polyline class="read-more-arrow" points="38 0.45 44.34 6.79 38.35 12.78"/></svg>Read More</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-large-font-size"> UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT SOUTHERN DISTRICT OF OHIO EASTERN DIVISION CASE NO.: 2:21-CV-05867-ALM-CMV</p>



<p class="has-regular-font-size">“On October 25, 2023, the Court in Andrews, et al. v. State Auto Mutual Insurance Company (S.D. Oh.) approved a class action settlement. The case revolved around allegations of breach of contract by the insurer, State Auto Mutual Insurance Company, for failing to pay the applicable Vehicle Sales Tax to insured individuals in Ohio, Illinois, and Missouri who had submitted physical damage claims for their vehicles following a total loss. The fact that State Auto agreed to provide up to $6.5 million in benefits as part of the settlement is a significant achievement. Normand PLLC played a key role in securing this compensation for the class members, particularly in relation to the unpaid Vehicle Sales Tax that the plaintiffs alleged they were owed under their insurance policies. This compensation aimed to rectify the damages suffered by class members due to State Auto&#8217;s alleged breach of contract. Normand PLLC worked diligently in representing the class members and securing a favorable settlement in the amount of $6,500,000 that aimed to compensate insured individuals who had been affected by State Auto&#8217;s alleged breach of contract, ultimately ensuring that nearly 100% of the damages owed were addressed through the settlement agreement.</p>



<p class="has-regular-font-size">On top of securing virtually 100% of the damages sought in the insurance class action lawsuit, Normand Law required the insurance company to pay all of the attorneys fees for each and every class member.  As a result, each class member was paid in full and had to pay nothing in attorney fees out of their recovery.  Taken together, such a result is virtually unheard of in class action settlements. Have you experienced a total loss? <a href="https://www.normandpllc.com/car-insurance-total-loss-claims/" data-type="post" data-id="438">Learn more</a>. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
